<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="null"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The Village Schoolteacher</title>
            <author>Liu Cixin</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  <xenoData><rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#" xmlns:as="http://www.w3.org/ns/activitystreams#" xmlns:cwrc="http://sparql.cwrc.ca/ontologies/cwrc#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/" xmlns:geo="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#" xmlns:oa="http://www.w3.org/ns/oa#" xmlns:schema="http://schema.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#" xmlns:fabio="https://purl.org/spar/fabio#" xmlns:bf="http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/bif#" xmlns:cito="https://sparontologies.github.io/cito/current/cito.html#" xmlns:org="http://www.w3.org/ns/org#">
        <rdf:Description rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/TR/json-ld/">
          <![CDATA[{
	"@context": {
		"dcterms:created": {
			"@type": "xsd:dateTime",
			"@id": "dcterms:created"
		},
		"dcterms:issued": {
			"@type": "xsd:dateTime",
			"@id": "dcterms:issued"
		},
		"oa:motivatedBy": {
			"@type": "oa:Motivation"
		},
		"@language": "en",
		"rdf": "http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#",
		"rdfs": "http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#",
		"as": "http://www.w3.org/ns/activitystreams#",
		"cwrc": "http://sparql.cwrc.ca/ontologies/cwrc#",
		"dc": "http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/",
		"dcterms": "http://purl.org/dc/terms/",
		"foaf": "http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/",
		"geo": "http://www.geonames.org/ontology#",
		"oa": "http://www.w3.org/ns/oa#",
		"schema": "http://schema.org/",
		"xsd": "http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#",
		"fabio": "https://purl.org/spar/fabio#",
		"bf": "http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/bif#",
		"cito": "https://sparontologies.github.io/cito/current/cito.html#",
		"org": "http://www.w3.org/ns/org#"
	},
	"id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Airuike72/my-work/main/TEI_project_Feng.xml?person_annotation_20240304092855067",
	"type": "oa:Annotation",
	"dcterms:created": "2024-03-04T14:28:55.067Z",
	"dcterms:creator": {
		"@id": "https://github.com/Airuike72",
		"@type": [
			"cwrc:NaturalPerson",
			"schema:Person"
		],
		"cwrc:hasName": "J Feng"
	},
	"oa:motivatedBy": "oa:identifying",
	"oa:hasTarget": {
		"@id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Airuike72/my-work/main/TEI_project_Feng.xml?person_annotation_20240304092855067#Target",
		"@type": "oa:SpecificResource",
		"oa:hasSource": {
			"@id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Airuike72/my-work/main/TEI_project_Feng.xml",
			"@type": "dctypes:Text",
			"dc:format": "text/xml"
		},
		"oa:renderedVia": {
			"@id": "https://leaf-writer.leaf-vre.org",
			"@type": "as:Application",
			"rdfs:label": "LEAF-Writer",
			"schema:softwareVersion": "3.4.0"
		},
		"oa:hasSelector": {
			"@id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Airuike72/my-work/main/TEI_project_Feng.xml?person_annotation_20240304092855067#Selector",
			"@type": "oa:XPathSelector",
			"rdf:value": "TEI/text/body/byline/persName"
		}
	},
	"oa:hasBody": {
		"@type": "cwrc:NaturalPerson",
		"@id": "http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q607588",
		"dc:format": "text/plain"
	},
	"as:generator": {
		"@id": "https://leaf-writer.leaf-vre.org",
		"@type": "as:Application",
		"rdfs:label": "LEAF-Writer",
		"schema:url": "https://leaf-writer.lincsproject.ca/",
		"schema:softwareVersion": "3.4.0"
	},
	"cwrc:hasCertainty": "cwrc:high"
}]]>
        </rdf:Description>
      
        <rdf:Description rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/TR/json-ld/">
          <![CDATA[{
	"@context": {
		"dcterms:created": {
			"@type": "xsd:dateTime",
			"@id": "dcterms:created"
		},
		"dcterms:issued": {
			"@type": "xsd:dateTime",
			"@id": "dcterms:issued"
		},
		"oa:motivatedBy": {
			"@type": "oa:Motivation"
		},
		"@language": "en",
		"rdf": "http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#",
		"rdfs": "http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#",
		"as": "http://www.w3.org/ns/activitystreams#",
		"cwrc": "http://sparql.cwrc.ca/ontologies/cwrc#",
		"dc": "http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/",
		"dcterms": "http://purl.org/dc/terms/",
		"foaf": "http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/",
		"geo": "http://www.geonames.org/ontology#",
		"oa": "http://www.w3.org/ns/oa#",
		"schema": "http://schema.org/",
		"xsd": "http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#",
		"fabio": "https://purl.org/spar/fabio#",
		"bf": "http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/bif#",
		"cito": "https://sparontologies.github.io/cito/current/cito.html#",
		"org": "http://www.w3.org/ns/org#"
	},
	"id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Airuike72/my-work/main/TEI_project_Feng.xml?person_annotation_20240304093123089",
	"type": "oa:Annotation",
	"dcterms:created": "2024-03-04T14:31:23.089Z",
	"dcterms:creator": {
		"@id": "https://github.com/Airuike72",
		"@type": [
			"cwrc:NaturalPerson",
			"schema:Person"
		],
		"cwrc:hasName": "J Feng"
	},
	"oa:motivatedBy": "oa:identifying",
	"oa:hasTarget": {
		"@id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Airuike72/my-work/main/TEI_project_Feng.xml?person_annotation_20240304093123089#Target",
		"@type": "oa:SpecificResource",
		"oa:hasSource": {
			"@id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Airuike72/my-work/main/TEI_project_Feng.xml",
			"@type": "dctypes:Text",
			"dc:format": "text/xml"
		},
		"oa:renderedVia": {
			"@id": "https://leaf-writer.leaf-vre.org",
			"@type": "as:Application",
			"rdfs:label": "LEAF-Writer",
			"schema:softwareVersion": "3.4.0"
		},
		"oa:hasSelector": {
			"@id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Airuike72/my-work/main/TEI_project_Feng.xml?person_annotation_20240304093123089#Selector",
			"@type": "oa:XPathSelector",
			"rdf:value": "TEI/text/body/p/persName[2]"
		}
	},
	"oa:hasBody": {
		"@type": "cwrc:NaturalPerson",
		"@id": "http://viaf.org/viaf/307441874/",
		"dc:format": "text/plain"
	},
	"as:generator": {
		"@id": "https://leaf-writer.leaf-vre.org",
		"@type": "as:Application",
		"rdfs:label": "LEAF-Writer",
		"schema:url": "https://leaf-writer.lincsproject.ca/",
		"schema:softwareVersion": "3.4.0"
	},
	"cwrc:hasCertainty": "cwrc:high"
}]]>
        </rdf:Description>
      </rdf:RDF></xenoData></teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <head>The Village Schoolteacher</head>
            <byline>By <persName key="Liu Cixin" ref="http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q607588" cert="high" role="aut" type="real">Liu Cixin</persName></byline>
            <p>Translated by <persName role="trl">Christopher Elford</persName> and <persName key="Jiang, Chenxin" ref="http://viaf.org/viaf/307441874/" cert="high" role="trl" type="real">Jiang Chenxin</persName>
</p><p>‘An exquisite, nearly perfect planetary system.’ said the Commander.</p>
            <p>The Chief Administrator agreed, ‘Yes. It’s small terrestrial planets and gaseous giants are deployed in a kind of rhyme scheme. The asteroid belt is perfectly positioned, like a beautiful jewelled necklace. The tiny icy outermost methane planet is like the last lingering note of a musical piece, hinting at the birth of a new era.’</p>
            <p>‘This is Blue 84210, preparing to scan for life on the innermost planet. Survey beam projected. This planet has no atmosphere and rotates very slowly on its axis. Surface temperatures vary greatly. Random location survey number 1. The result is white. Random location survey number 2. The result is white ... Random location survey number 10. The result is white. Blue 84210 reporting. This planet contains no life.’</p>
            <p>The Commander said with disapprobation, ‘This planet’s surface could be used as a smelter. There’s no need to waste any more time!’</p>
            <p>‘Initiate life scan on the second planet. Projecting beam sent. This planet has a thick atmosphere. Surface temperatures are high and relatively homogenous, mostly covered by acidic clouds. Random location survey number 1. The result is white. Random location survey number 2. The result is white ... Random location survey number 10. The result is white. Blue 84210 reporting. This planet contains no life.’</p>
            <p>Using four-dimensional communication, the Chief Administrator said to the officers on board Blue 84210 more than 1,000 light years away, ‘My intuition tells me that that there is a great probability of life on the third planet. Initiate thirty random locations surveys.’</p>
            <p>‘Sir, we are pressed for time,’ the Commander said.</p>
            <p>‘Do as I say,’ the Chief Administrator said firmly.</p>
            <p>‘Sir, yes sir. Initiating survey of the third planet. Projecting beam sent. This planet has an average atmospheric density. Most of its surface is covered by ocean.’</p><p>THE LIFE SURVEY BEAM fell on a slightly southerly portion of the Asian continent. The tip of the beam formed a circle on the ground with a diameter of roughly five thousand metres. If it was daylight, one could detect the beam with the naked eye as all non-living things within the beam’s range became transparent when it hit them. It now shone on a small mountainous region in north-western China, and the loess slopes would have looked to an observer like crystal. The sun would have refracted in and out of these mountains, creating a truly magnificent scene. The observer would have seen the ground below him transformed into a bottomless abyss. All things determined to be living remained unchanged. People, trees, and grass would have stood out with utter clarity in this crystalline world. But this effect would only have lasted for half a second. During this time the scanning beam would have already completed its initial scan and everything would have returned to normal. The observer would have thought it a momentary hallucination. But right now it was night and naturally it was difficult to notice anything.</p><p>The village school happened to be right at the centre of the circle made by the survey beam.</p><p>‘RANDOM LOCATION SURVEY number 1. The result is ... green! The result is green! Blue 84210 reporting. Target 500921473. The third planet contains life!’</p><p>The survey beam began to classify the many kinds of life that fell within its range, ranking the species according to the complexity of their structure and their estimated stages of intelligence, and putting them in order in its digital database. The group of creatures under a square shelter were ranked at the top. The beam speedily retracted, focusing on that shelter.</p><p>The Chief Administrator’s intelligence field received Blue 84210’s image and enlarged it to cover the entire space background. That image of the village schoolhouse in an instant covered the entire universe. The image processing system had already removed the shelter, but the images of the life forms were still unclear. These life forms’ appearance was not eye-catching in the slightest and even seemed to blend in with the silicas and yellow dirt that surrounded them. The main computer could not but eliminate from the image everything lifeless, including the larger dead form that was surrounded by the life forms, making them look as though they were suspended alone in the vast emptiness. Even this way they seemed rather ordinary, devoid of colour, looking like yellow plants. One look and you knew these creatures weren’t capable of performing miracles.</p><p>Blue 84210 projected a thin four-dimensional beam. The moon-sized ship had anchored just outside Jupiter’s orbit, temporarily providing the solar system with an additional planet. The four-dimensional beam moved through three- dimensional space toward Earth at almost infinite speed. It plunged straight through the roof of the school and began conducting an elementary particle scan on the eighteen children. The torrent of information returned to space at a speed scarcely conceivable to humans. In an instant the children’s digital replicas had been assembled in Blue 84210’s main computer’s database, a database more vast than the universe itself.</p><p>The eighteen children were suspended in a boundless space of a colour impossible to describe, not really a colour at all since the void does not have a colour but is more transparent than transparent. The children couldn’t help but grab onto each other. They looked normal but their hands passed through each other’s bodies without the slightest obstruction. The children felt an indescribable terror. The main computer observed this, and thinking that these life forms needed familiar objects, it created in its own internal universe a blue that mimicked that of the planet’s sky. The children immediately looked up at the blue sky, with no sun and no clouds and no dust, just blue, so pure and profound. There was no ground under their feet but a sky same as the one over their heads. They seemed to be in a universe of endless blue, and they were the only substance in it. The computer felt that these digital life forms were still in panic and in a millionth of a second, understood: most of the living things in the Milky Way galaxy were not afraid of being suspended in space, but these life forms were not the same. They were land creatures. It therefore provided them with ground and a feeling of gravity. The children were surprised to see the ground suddenly appear beneath their feet. It was pure white and its surface was criss-crossed with an orderly black and white grid. They seemed to be standing on a gridded writing practice book that extended to infinity. Some of them bent down to touch it. It was the smoothest thing any of them had ever seen. They took long strides but did not move, as the surface was absolutely smooth, the coefficient of friction was zero. They wondered why they did not fall down. One of the children took off a shoe and slid it across the ground. This shoe slid forward at a uniform speed. The children stared as it moved off into the distance at an unchanging speed.</p><p>They had seen Newton’s first law.</p><p>After graduating from middle school, he had given up his chance to get a good job in the
            township government and returned instead to this destitute mountain village, to the school his
            teacher had worried so much about. By then the school had already been abandoned for a
            number of years.</p>          
            <p>Not long before this the Ministry of Education had announced a new policy directive. They were
            discontinuing the ‘locally-sponsored teachers’, with those who could pass their examinations to
            become ‘state-certified teachers’. When he received his teaching certificate, showing that he was
            now a nationally certified primary school teacher, he was happy, but merely happy, not elated as
            his colleagues had been. He didn’t care about the difference between locally-sponsored and state-
            certified. All he cared about were the children who passed through his classroom: that they might
            graduate and go out into the world. Whether they stayed in or left the mountains didn’t matter;
            their lives would always be a little different from the lives of those who had never attended a day
            of school.</p>
            <p>This desolate mountainous region was one of the poorest in the entire country. But being poor
            wasn’t the worst of it. The worst was how numb to their condition people had become. He
            remembered many years ago, when it came time to fix household farm quotas, the village began
            dividing up the fields and then went on to divide up other things. As for the village’s only tractor,
            nobody could decide how to divide the cost of fuel or arrange a time schedule for its use. Finally
            they settled on the only solution everyone could live with and divided up the tractor itself.
            Literally divided it up: you’ll take the wheels, they’ll take the axle.</p>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>