<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="null"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The Village Schoolteacher</title>
            <author>Liu Cixin</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  <xenoData><rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#" xmlns:as="http://www.w3.org/ns/activitystreams#" xmlns:cwrc="http://sparql.cwrc.ca/ontologies/cwrc#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/" xmlns:geo="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#" xmlns:oa="http://www.w3.org/ns/oa#" xmlns:schema="http://schema.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#" xmlns:fabio="https://purl.org/spar/fabio#" xmlns:bf="http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/bif#" xmlns:cito="https://sparontologies.github.io/cito/current/cito.html#" xmlns:org="http://www.w3.org/ns/org#">
        <rdf:Description rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/TR/json-ld/">
          <![CDATA[{
	"@context": {
		"dcterms:created": {
			"@type": "xsd:dateTime",
			"@id": "dcterms:created"
		},
		"dcterms:issued": {
			"@type": "xsd:dateTime",
			"@id": "dcterms:issued"
		},
		"oa:motivatedBy": {
			"@type": "oa:Motivation"
		},
		"@language": "en",
		"rdf": "http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#",
		"rdfs": "http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#",
		"as": "http://www.w3.org/ns/activitystreams#",
		"cwrc": "http://sparql.cwrc.ca/ontologies/cwrc#",
		"dc": "http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/",
		"dcterms": "http://purl.org/dc/terms/",
		"foaf": "http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/",
		"geo": "http://www.geonames.org/ontology#",
		"oa": "http://www.w3.org/ns/oa#",
		"schema": "http://schema.org/",
		"xsd": "http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#",
		"fabio": "https://purl.org/spar/fabio#",
		"bf": "http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/bif#",
		"cito": "https://sparontologies.github.io/cito/current/cito.html#",
		"org": "http://www.w3.org/ns/org#"
	},
	"id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Airuike72/my-work/main/TEI_project_Feng.xml?person_annotation_20240304092855067",
	"type": "oa:Annotation",
	"dcterms:created": "2024-03-04T14:28:55.067Z",
	"dcterms:creator": {
		"@id": "https://github.com/Airuike72",
		"@type": [
			"cwrc:NaturalPerson",
			"schema:Person"
		],
		"cwrc:hasName": "J Feng"
	},
	"oa:motivatedBy": "oa:identifying",
	"oa:hasTarget": {
		"@id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Airuike72/my-work/main/TEI_project_Feng.xml?person_annotation_20240304092855067#Target",
		"@type": "oa:SpecificResource",
		"oa:hasSource": {
			"@id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Airuike72/my-work/main/TEI_project_Feng.xml",
			"@type": "dctypes:Text",
			"dc:format": "text/xml"
		},
		"oa:renderedVia": {
			"@id": "https://leaf-writer.leaf-vre.org",
			"@type": "as:Application",
			"rdfs:label": "LEAF-Writer",
			"schema:softwareVersion": "3.4.0"
		},
		"oa:hasSelector": {
			"@id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Airuike72/my-work/main/TEI_project_Feng.xml?person_annotation_20240304092855067#Selector",
			"@type": "oa:XPathSelector",
			"rdf:value": "TEI/text/body/byline/persName"
		}
	},
	"oa:hasBody": {
		"@type": "cwrc:NaturalPerson",
		"@id": "http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q607588",
		"dc:format": "text/plain"
	},
	"as:generator": {
		"@id": "https://leaf-writer.leaf-vre.org",
		"@type": "as:Application",
		"rdfs:label": "LEAF-Writer",
		"schema:url": "https://leaf-writer.lincsproject.ca/",
		"schema:softwareVersion": "3.4.0"
	},
	"cwrc:hasCertainty": "cwrc:high"
}]]>
        </rdf:Description>
      
        <rdf:Description rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/TR/json-ld/">
          <![CDATA[{
	"@context": {
		"dcterms:created": {
			"@type": "xsd:dateTime",
			"@id": "dcterms:created"
		},
		"dcterms:issued": {
			"@type": "xsd:dateTime",
			"@id": "dcterms:issued"
		},
		"oa:motivatedBy": {
			"@type": "oa:Motivation"
		},
		"@language": "en",
		"rdf": "http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#",
		"rdfs": "http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#",
		"as": "http://www.w3.org/ns/activitystreams#",
		"cwrc": "http://sparql.cwrc.ca/ontologies/cwrc#",
		"dc": "http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/",
		"dcterms": "http://purl.org/dc/terms/",
		"foaf": "http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/",
		"geo": "http://www.geonames.org/ontology#",
		"oa": "http://www.w3.org/ns/oa#",
		"schema": "http://schema.org/",
		"xsd": "http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#",
		"fabio": "https://purl.org/spar/fabio#",
		"bf": "http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/bif#",
		"cito": "https://sparontologies.github.io/cito/current/cito.html#",
		"org": "http://www.w3.org/ns/org#"
	},
	"id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Airuike72/my-work/main/TEI_project_Feng.xml?person_annotation_20240304093123089",
	"type": "oa:Annotation",
	"dcterms:created": "2024-03-04T14:31:23.089Z",
	"dcterms:creator": {
		"@id": "https://github.com/Airuike72",
		"@type": [
			"cwrc:NaturalPerson",
			"schema:Person"
		],
		"cwrc:hasName": "J Feng"
	},
	"oa:motivatedBy": "oa:identifying",
	"oa:hasTarget": {
		"@id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Airuike72/my-work/main/TEI_project_Feng.xml?person_annotation_20240304093123089#Target",
		"@type": "oa:SpecificResource",
		"oa:hasSource": {
			"@id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Airuike72/my-work/main/TEI_project_Feng.xml",
			"@type": "dctypes:Text",
			"dc:format": "text/xml"
		},
		"oa:renderedVia": {
			"@id": "https://leaf-writer.leaf-vre.org",
			"@type": "as:Application",
			"rdfs:label": "LEAF-Writer",
			"schema:softwareVersion": "3.4.0"
		},
		"oa:hasSelector": {
			"@id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Airuike72/my-work/main/TEI_project_Feng.xml?person_annotation_20240304093123089#Selector",
			"@type": "oa:XPathSelector",
			"rdf:value": "TEI/text/body/p/persName[2]"
		}
	},
	"oa:hasBody": {
		"@type": "cwrc:NaturalPerson",
		"@id": "http://viaf.org/viaf/307441874/",
		"dc:format": "text/plain"
	},
	"as:generator": {
		"@id": "https://leaf-writer.leaf-vre.org",
		"@type": "as:Application",
		"rdfs:label": "LEAF-Writer",
		"schema:url": "https://leaf-writer.lincsproject.ca/",
		"schema:softwareVersion": "3.4.0"
	},
	"cwrc:hasCertainty": "cwrc:high"
}]]>
        </rdf:Description>
      </rdf:RDF></xenoData></teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <head>The Village Schoolteacher</head>
            <byline>By <persName key="Liu Cixin" ref="http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q607588" cert="high" role="aut" type="real">Liu Cixin</persName></byline>
            <p>Translated by <persName role="trl">Christopher Elford</persName> and <persName key="Jiang, Chenxin" ref="http://viaf.org/viaf/307441874/" cert="high" role="trl" type="real">Jiang Chenxin</persName>
</p><p>‘An exquisite, nearly perfect planetary system.’ said the Commander.</p>
            <p>The Chief Administrator agreed, ‘Yes. It’s small terrestrial planets and gaseous giants are deployed in a kind of rhyme scheme. The asteroid belt is perfectly positioned, like a beautiful jewelled necklace. The tiny icy outermost methane planet is like the last lingering note of a musical piece, hinting at the birth of a new era.’</p>
            <p>‘This is Blue 84210, preparing to scan for life on the innermost planet. Survey beam projected. This planet has no atmosphere and rotates very slowly on its axis. Surface temperatures vary greatly. Random location survey number 1. The result is white. Random location survey number 2. The result is white ... Random location survey number 10. The result is white. Blue 84210 reporting. This planet contains no life.’</p>
            <p>The Commander said with disapprobation, ‘This planet’s surface could be used as a smelter. There’s no need to waste any more time!’</p>
            <p>‘Initiate life scan on the second planet. Projecting beam sent. This planet has a thick atmosphere. Surface temperatures are high and relatively homogenous, mostly covered by acidic clouds. Random location survey number 1. The result is white. Random location survey number 2. The result is white ... Random location survey number 10. The result is white. Blue 84210 reporting. This planet contains no life.’</p>
            <p>Using four-dimensional communication, the Chief Administrator said to the officers on board Blue 84210 more than 1,000 light years away, ‘My intuition tells me that that there is a great probability of life on the third planet. Initiate thirty random locations surveys.’</p>
            <p>‘Sir, we are pressed for time,’ the Commander said.</p>
            <p>‘Do as I say,’ the Chief Administrator said firmly.</p>
            <p>Children and firelight, children and firelight. Always children and firelight, always children and
            firelight at night. It was what this world had burned into his mind, this image, and yet he never
            understood exactly what it meant.</p>
            <p>He knew they were burning the incense and spirit-money for him. They had done it many times
            before, but this time he didn’t have the strength to go out and reprimand them for being
            superstitious. He had spent his entire life lighting the fires of science and civilization in their
            hearts but he knew that in a remote mountain village shrouded in ignorance, the fires he lit were
            small in comparison to the fires of superstition, like the candle he held against the blackboard in
            a freezing cold classroom deep in the mountains on a dark winter’s night. Six months earlier
            some villagers had taken the rafters from the already run-down school dormitory. They said they
            needed them to fix the old temple. When he asked how the dormers would get on without a roof
            over their heads they said the kids could sleep in the classroom. When he reminded them that the
            classroom let in drafts on all sides and asked what the children would do in the winter, they said,
            ‘Well, they’re all children from other villages anyway.’ He went after them with a bamboo
            shoulder-pole and ended up with two broken ribs in the resulting fight. A couple of decent people
            took him thirty kilometres to the township hospital.</p>
            <p>During his check-up they discovered by chance that he had cancer of the oesophagus. There was
            nothing strange about this, as the area was a high-risk zone for oesophageal cancer. The doctor
            congratulated him on his happy turn of fortune. The cancer was still in its early stages and hadn’t
            yet begun to spread; a simple operation would take care of it. Oesophageal cancer has a high
            post- operative recovery rate. He was lucky.</p>
            <p>He had come all the way to the city and was in the cancer ward when he asked the doctor how
            much the operation would cost. The doctor replied that given his situation he would be qualified
            to move to the poverty-relief ward and other costs could also be reduced, making the final sum
            not large, probably around 20,000 yuan. Seeing as he had come from a remote mountain area, the
            doctor explained in great detail the procedure for staying in the hospital. He listened quietly and
            then asked abruptly, ‘If we don’t operate, about how long do I have?’ The doctor stared at him
            blankly for a moment before saying, ‘About half a year.’ The doctor then looked confused as he
            let out a sigh of relief, as if he had been greatly reassured.</p>            
            <p>At least he would be able to send off this year’s graduating class.</p>
            <p>He really couldn’t afford the 20,000 yuan. The salaries of locally-sponsored teachers were low,
            but since he had worked for many years and had only himself to worry about, it would be
            reasonable to suppose that he would have some savings. But he had spent all that money on his
            students, and could not remember how many times he had helped to pay tuition and other fees.
            Most recently it had been for Baozhu and Cuihua. Many times he had noticed that the food
            cooking in the pots lacked oil so he had used his own money to buy meat and lard for them ...
</p><p>            Now he had only about one-tenth of what it would take to pay for the operation.</p>
            <p>Following one of the wide city avenues, he walked in the direction of the train station. It was
            dark and the neon lights were already casting their enchanting glow across the cityscape, a
            gorgeous radiance that baffled him; when night fell, the tall buildings turned into giant multi-
            coloured lanterns. The music that drifted through the night air was frenzied and mellow by turns.
            In a world that he had never been a part of, he thought back on his relatively short life. He was
            calm; each person had his own life to live. Returning to his primary school in the mountains
            twenty years ago after graduating from middle school had sealed his fate. Besides, he owed the
            greater part of his life to another village schoolteacher. The school he was now in charge of was
            the one he’d spent his childhood attending. His mother and father had died early and so the crude
            school was his only home. His teacher had taken him in and treated him like a son.</p>
            <p>Even though they were poor, his childhood had not been without love. One winter, when school
            let out for the holiday, his teacher brought him to his own home. His teacher’s house was far
            away and they had to travel down long mountain roads packed with snow. By the time they
            caught sight of the dim lights burning in his teacher’s village it was already midnight. It was then
            that they saw behind them four small green shimmering discs of light. Wolves’ eyes. At the time
            there were still many wolves in the mountains and one could see piles of wolf droppings near the
            schoolhouse. He’d been naughty once, igniting and tossing the whitish grey lumps into the
            classroom, filling it with heavy smoke. The children had bolted out of the classroom choking and
            his teacher had been very angry. Now the wolves behind them were slowly drawing close. His
            teacher broke off a thick tree branch and waved it in their path to block their approach, shouting
            for him to run into the village. He was out of his mind with fear, and could only run, could only
            think about the possibility of the wolves bypassing his teacher to get at him, could only think
            there might be other wolves. He ran, breathless, into the village, and returned with several men
            carrying guns to help his teacher. They discovered him lying in a frozen pool of blood, with half
            a leg missing and one entire arm ripped off. It was on the road to the hospital that his teacher
            breathed his last. He had caught a glimpse of his teacher’s eyes in the torchlight and the deep bite
            on the side of his cheek where a large chunk of flesh had been torn off. Although his teacher
            could no longer speak, he had used his eyes to communicate a most urgent and sincere concern.
            He understood this. He would never forget it.</p>
            <p>After graduating from middle school, he had given up his chance to get a good job in the
            township government and returned instead to this destitute mountain village, to the school his
            teacher had worried so much about. By then the school had already been abandoned for a
            number of years. </p>          
            <p>Not long before this the Ministry of Education had announced a new policy directive. They were
            discontinuing the ‘locally-sponsored teachers’, with those who could pass their examinations to
            become ‘state-certified teachers’. When he received his teaching certificate, showing that he was
            now a nationally certified primary school teacher, he was happy, but merely happy, not elated as
            his colleagues had been. He didn’t care about the difference between locally-sponsored and state-
            certified. All he cared about were the children who passed through his classroom: that they might
            graduate and go out into the world. Whether they stayed in or left the mountains didn’t matter;
            their lives would always be a little different from the lives of those who had never attended a day
            of school.</p>
            <p>This desolate mountainous region was one of the poorest in the entire country. But being poor
            wasn’t the worst of it. The worst was how numb to their condition people had become. He
            remembered many years ago, when it came time to fix household farm quotas, the village began
            dividing up the fields and then went on to divide up other things. As for the village’s only tractor,
            nobody could decide how to divide the cost of fuel or arrange a time schedule for its use. Finally
            they settled on the only solution everyone could live with and divided up the tractor itself.
            Literally divided it up: you’ll take the wheels, they’ll take the axle.</p>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>