<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="null"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The Village Schoolteacher</title>
            <author>Liu Cixin</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  <xenoData><rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#" xmlns:as="http://www.w3.org/ns/activitystreams#" xmlns:cwrc="http://sparql.cwrc.ca/ontologies/cwrc#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/" xmlns:geo="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#" xmlns:oa="http://www.w3.org/ns/oa#" xmlns:schema="http://schema.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#" xmlns:fabio="https://purl.org/spar/fabio#" xmlns:bf="http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/bif#" xmlns:cito="https://sparontologies.github.io/cito/current/cito.html#" xmlns:org="http://www.w3.org/ns/org#">
        <rdf:Description rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/TR/json-ld/">
          <![CDATA[{
	"@context": {
		"dcterms:created": {
			"@type": "xsd:dateTime",
			"@id": "dcterms:created"
		},
		"dcterms:issued": {
			"@type": "xsd:dateTime",
			"@id": "dcterms:issued"
		},
		"oa:motivatedBy": {
			"@type": "oa:Motivation"
		},
		"@language": "en",
		"rdf": "http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#",
		"rdfs": "http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#",
		"as": "http://www.w3.org/ns/activitystreams#",
		"cwrc": "http://sparql.cwrc.ca/ontologies/cwrc#",
		"dc": "http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/",
		"dcterms": "http://purl.org/dc/terms/",
		"foaf": "http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/",
		"geo": "http://www.geonames.org/ontology#",
		"oa": "http://www.w3.org/ns/oa#",
		"schema": "http://schema.org/",
		"xsd": "http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#",
		"fabio": "https://purl.org/spar/fabio#",
		"bf": "http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/bif#",
		"cito": "https://sparontologies.github.io/cito/current/cito.html#",
		"org": "http://www.w3.org/ns/org#"
	},
	"id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Airuike72/my-work/main/TEI_project_Feng.xml?person_annotation_20240304092855067",
	"type": "oa:Annotation",
	"dcterms:created": "2024-03-04T14:28:55.067Z",
	"dcterms:creator": {
		"@id": "https://github.com/Airuike72",
		"@type": [
			"cwrc:NaturalPerson",
			"schema:Person"
		],
		"cwrc:hasName": "J Feng"
	},
	"oa:motivatedBy": "oa:identifying",
	"oa:hasTarget": {
		"@id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Airuike72/my-work/main/TEI_project_Feng.xml?person_annotation_20240304092855067#Target",
		"@type": "oa:SpecificResource",
		"oa:hasSource": {
			"@id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Airuike72/my-work/main/TEI_project_Feng.xml",
			"@type": "dctypes:Text",
			"dc:format": "text/xml"
		},
		"oa:renderedVia": {
			"@id": "https://leaf-writer.leaf-vre.org",
			"@type": "as:Application",
			"rdfs:label": "LEAF-Writer",
			"schema:softwareVersion": "3.4.0"
		},
		"oa:hasSelector": {
			"@id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Airuike72/my-work/main/TEI_project_Feng.xml?person_annotation_20240304092855067#Selector",
			"@type": "oa:XPathSelector",
			"rdf:value": "TEI/text/body/byline/persName"
		}
	},
	"oa:hasBody": {
		"@type": "cwrc:NaturalPerson",
		"@id": "http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q607588",
		"dc:format": "text/plain"
	},
	"as:generator": {
		"@id": "https://leaf-writer.leaf-vre.org",
		"@type": "as:Application",
		"rdfs:label": "LEAF-Writer",
		"schema:url": "https://leaf-writer.lincsproject.ca/",
		"schema:softwareVersion": "3.4.0"
	},
	"cwrc:hasCertainty": "cwrc:high"
}]]>
        </rdf:Description>
      
        <rdf:Description rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/TR/json-ld/">
          <![CDATA[{
	"@context": {
		"dcterms:created": {
			"@type": "xsd:dateTime",
			"@id": "dcterms:created"
		},
		"dcterms:issued": {
			"@type": "xsd:dateTime",
			"@id": "dcterms:issued"
		},
		"oa:motivatedBy": {
			"@type": "oa:Motivation"
		},
		"@language": "en",
		"rdf": "http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#",
		"rdfs": "http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#",
		"as": "http://www.w3.org/ns/activitystreams#",
		"cwrc": "http://sparql.cwrc.ca/ontologies/cwrc#",
		"dc": "http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/",
		"dcterms": "http://purl.org/dc/terms/",
		"foaf": "http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/",
		"geo": "http://www.geonames.org/ontology#",
		"oa": "http://www.w3.org/ns/oa#",
		"schema": "http://schema.org/",
		"xsd": "http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#",
		"fabio": "https://purl.org/spar/fabio#",
		"bf": "http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/bif#",
		"cito": "https://sparontologies.github.io/cito/current/cito.html#",
		"org": "http://www.w3.org/ns/org#"
	},
	"id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Airuike72/my-work/main/TEI_project_Feng.xml?person_annotation_20240304093123089",
	"type": "oa:Annotation",
	"dcterms:created": "2024-03-04T14:31:23.089Z",
	"dcterms:creator": {
		"@id": "https://github.com/Airuike72",
		"@type": [
			"cwrc:NaturalPerson",
			"schema:Person"
		],
		"cwrc:hasName": "J Feng"
	},
	"oa:motivatedBy": "oa:identifying",
	"oa:hasTarget": {
		"@id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Airuike72/my-work/main/TEI_project_Feng.xml?person_annotation_20240304093123089#Target",
		"@type": "oa:SpecificResource",
		"oa:hasSource": {
			"@id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Airuike72/my-work/main/TEI_project_Feng.xml",
			"@type": "dctypes:Text",
			"dc:format": "text/xml"
		},
		"oa:renderedVia": {
			"@id": "https://leaf-writer.leaf-vre.org",
			"@type": "as:Application",
			"rdfs:label": "LEAF-Writer",
			"schema:softwareVersion": "3.4.0"
		},
		"oa:hasSelector": {
			"@id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Airuike72/my-work/main/TEI_project_Feng.xml?person_annotation_20240304093123089#Selector",
			"@type": "oa:XPathSelector",
			"rdf:value": "TEI/text/body/p/persName[2]"
		}
	},
	"oa:hasBody": {
		"@type": "cwrc:NaturalPerson",
		"@id": "http://viaf.org/viaf/307441874/",
		"dc:format": "text/plain"
	},
	"as:generator": {
		"@id": "https://leaf-writer.leaf-vre.org",
		"@type": "as:Application",
		"rdfs:label": "LEAF-Writer",
		"schema:url": "https://leaf-writer.lincsproject.ca/",
		"schema:softwareVersion": "3.4.0"
	},
	"cwrc:hasCertainty": "cwrc:high"
}]]>
        </rdf:Description>
      </rdf:RDF></xenoData></teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <head>The Village Schoolteacher</head>
            <byline>By <persName key="Liu Cixin" ref="http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q607588" cert="high" role="aut" type="real">Liu Cixin</persName></byline>
            <p>Translated by <persName role="trl">Christopher Elford</persName> and <persName key="Jiang, Chenxin" ref="http://viaf.org/viaf/307441874/" cert="high" role="trl" type="real">Jiang Chenxin</persName>
</p><p>‘An exquisite, nearly perfect planetary system.’ said the Commander.</p>
            <p>The Chief Administrator agreed, ‘Yes. It’s small terrestrial planets and gaseous giants are deployed in a kind of rhyme scheme. The asteroid belt is perfectly positioned, like a beautiful jewelled necklace. The tiny icy outermost methane planet is like the last lingering note of a musical piece, hinting at the birth of a new era.’</p>
            <p>‘This is Blue 84210, preparing to scan for life on the innermost planet. Survey beam projected. This planet has no atmosphere and rotates very slowly on its axis. Surface temperatures vary greatly. Random location survey number 1. The result is white. Random location survey number 2. The result is white ... Random location survey number 10. The result is white. Blue 84210 reporting. This planet contains no life.’</p>
            <p>The Commander said with disapprobation, ‘This planet’s surface could be used as a smelter. There’s no need to waste any more time!’</p>
            <p>‘Initiate life scan on the second planet. Projecting beam sent. This planet has a thick atmosphere. Surface temperatures are high and relatively homogenous, mostly covered by acidic clouds. Random location survey number 1. The result is white. Random location survey number 2. The result is white ... Random location survey number 10. The result is white. Blue 84210 reporting. This planet contains no life.’</p>
            <p>Using four-dimensional communication, the Chief Administrator said to the officers on board Blue 84210 more than 1,000 light years away, ‘My intuition tells me that that there is a great probability of life on the third planet. Initiate thirty random locations surveys.’</p>
            <p>‘Sir, we are pressed for time,’ the Commander said.</p>
            <p>‘Do as I say,’ the Chief Administrator said firmly.</p>
            <p>‘Sir, yes sir. Initiating survey of the third planet. Projecting beam sent. This planet has an average atmospheric density. Most of its surface is covered by ocean.’</p><p>THE LIFE SURVEY BEAM fell on a slightly southerly portion of the Asian continent. The tip of the beam formed a circle on the ground with a diameter of roughly five thousand metres. If it was daylight, one could detect the beam with the naked eye as all non-living things within the beam’s range became transparent when it hit them. It now shone on a small mountainous region in north-western China, and the loess slopes would have looked to an observer like crystal. The sun would have refracted in and out of these mountains, creating a truly magnificent scene. The observer would have seen the ground below him transformed into a bottomless abyss. All things determined to be living remained unchanged. People, trees, and grass would have stood out with utter clarity in this crystalline world. But this effect would only have lasted for half a second. During this time the scanning beam would have already completed its initial scan and everything would have returned to normal. The observer would have thought it a momentary hallucination. But right now it was night and naturally it was difficult to notice anything.</p><p>The village school happened to be right at the centre of the circle made by the survey beam.</p><p>‘RANDOM LOCATION SURVEY number 1. The result is ... green! The result is green! Blue 84210 reporting. Target 500921473. The third planet contains life!’</p><p>The survey beam began to classify the many kinds of life that fell within its range, ranking the species according to the complexity of their structure and their estimated stages of intelligence, and putting them in order in its digital database. The group of creatures under a square shelter were ranked at the top. The beam speedily retracted, focusing on that shelter.</p><p>The Chief Administrator’s intelligence field received Blue 84210’s image and enlarged it to cover the entire space background. That image of the village schoolhouse in an instant covered the entire universe. The image processing system had already removed the shelter, but the images of the life forms were still unclear. These life forms’ appearance was not eye-catching in the slightest and even seemed to blend in with the silicas and yellow dirt that surrounded them. The main computer could not but eliminate from the image everything lifeless, including the larger dead form that was surrounded by the life forms, making them look as though they were suspended alone in the vast emptiness. Even this way they seemed rather ordinary, devoid of colour, looking like yellow plants. One look and you knew these creatures weren’t capable of performing miracles.</p><p>Blue 84210 projected a thin four-dimensional beam. The moon-sized ship had anchored just outside Jupiter’s orbit, temporarily providing the solar system with an additional planet. The four-dimensional beam moved through three- dimensional space toward Earth at almost infinite speed. It plunged straight through the roof of the school and began conducting an elementary particle scan on the eighteen children. The torrent of information returned to space at a speed scarcely conceivable to humans. In an instant the children’s digital replicas had been assembled in Blue 84210’s main computer’s database, a database more vast than the universe itself.</p><p>The eighteen children were suspended in a boundless space of a colour impossible to describe, not really a colour at all since the void does not have a colour but is more transparent than transparent. The children couldn’t help but grab onto each other. They looked normal but their hands passed through each other’s bodies without the slightest obstruction. The children felt an indescribable terror. The main computer observed this, and thinking that these life forms needed familiar objects, it created in its own internal universe a blue that mimicked that of the planet’s sky. The children immediately looked up at the blue sky, with no sun and no clouds and no dust, just blue, so pure and profound. There was no ground under their feet but a sky same as the one over their heads. They seemed to be in a universe of endless blue, and they were the only substance in it. The computer felt that these digital life forms were still in panic and in a millionth of a second, understood: most of the living things in the Milky Way galaxy were not afraid of being suspended in space, but these life forms were not the same. They were land creatures. It therefore provided them with ground and a feeling of gravity. The children were surprised to see the ground suddenly appear beneath their feet. It was pure white and its surface was criss-crossed with an orderly black and white grid. They seemed to be standing on a gridded writing practice book that extended to infinity. Some of them bent down to touch it. It was the smoothest thing any of them had ever seen. They took long strides but did not move, as the surface was absolutely smooth, the coefficient of friction was zero. They wondered why they did not fall down. One of the children took off a shoe and slid it across the ground. This shoe slid forward at a uniform speed. The children stared as it moved off into the distance at an unchanging speed.</p><p>They had seen Newton’s first law.</p><p>A sound, gentle and lovely, resounded in the digital universe.</p><p>‘Begin the 3C Civilization Test. 3C Civilization Test question number 1: Please describe the evolutionary principle of life on your planet. Is it natural selection or gene mutation?’</p><p>The children remained in stupefied silence.</p><p>‘3C Civilization Test question number 2: Please briefly state the source of the stars’ energy.’</p><p>The children still remained in stupefied silence.</p><p>...</p><p>‘3C Civilization Test question number 10: Please explain the molecular structure of the liquid which fills your oceans.’</p><p>The stupefied silence continued.</p><p>The shoe, now only a tiny dot on the horizon, disappeared.</p><p>‘Let’s stop here.’ the Commander said to the Chief Administrator 1,000 light years away. ‘We cannot delay any longer, or we won’t be able to complete the first stage of the mission on time.’</p><p>The Chief Administrator’s intelligence field rippled slightly to signal agreement. ‘Launch the singularity bomb!’</p><p>The beam carrying this information travelled through four-dimensional space and arrived in an instant at Blue 84210, anchored in the middle of the solar system. A faintly glowing foggy ball slid out of the front of the battleship and down the long guide rail, following an invisible tractor beam as it swiftly gathered speed and hurtled toward the sun.</p><p>The Chief Administrator, the Senator, and the Fleet Commander turned their attention to other areas of the quarantine zone, where they found a few more planetary systems that contained life. But the highest form of life they found was a brainless worm that lived in mud. The exploding stars looked like blossoming fireworks, reminding them of the epic Campaign of the Second Spiral Arm.</p><p>After a long time, a small portion of the Chief Administrator’s intelligence field unconsciously wandered to the solar system. He heard the voice of Blue 84210’s captain:</p><p>‘Prepare to exit the force field of the explosion. Ready for space-time jump. Thirty second countdown.’</p><p>‘Wait, how long will it take for the singularity bomb to hit the target?’ the Chief Administrator asked. His question attracted the attention of the Senator and the Fleet Commander.</p><p>‘It is crossing the orbit of the innermost planet to the star, so it will take another ten minutes.’</p><p>‘Spend the next five minutes doing a few more tests.’</p><p>The voice of Blue 84210’s duty-officer rang out. ‘ 3C Civilization Test question number 11: On a three-dimensional plane, what is the relation between the three sides of a right-angled triangle?’</p><p>Silence.</p><p>‘3C Civilization Test question number 12: What number planet is your planet within your solar system?’</p><p>Silence.</p><p>‘Sir, this is pointless,’ the Commander said.</p><p>‘3C Civilization Test question number 13: Describe the motion of a body when unaffected by external force.’</p><p>The children’s clear voices suddenly sounded out through the wide blue space of the digital universe: ‘A body continues in its state of rest, or of uniform motion in a straight line, when it is not compelled to change that state by external force.’</p><p>‘Question number 13 passed! 3C Civilization Test question number 14 ...’</p><p>‘Wait!’ The Senator interrupted the duty-officer. ‘Choose the next question on the laws of motion at low speeds.’ He turned to the Chief Administrator. ‘This doesn’t contravene the rules of the test, does it?’</p><p>‘Of course not, as long as the test questions are from the digital test database,’ the Commander answered instead. These living beings had surprised him and captured his full attention.</p><p>‘3C Civilization Test question number 14: Describe the interaction between two bodies when one exerts a force on the other.’</p><p>The children replied in unison: ‘Whenever one body exerts a force onto a second body, the second body exerts a force on the first. The two forces are equal in magnitude and opposite in direction.’</p><p>‘Question number 14 passed! 3C Civilization Test question number 15: Explain the relation between the mass of a body, its acceleration, and the force exerted on it.’</p><p>The children chanted: ‘The acceleration of a body is directly proportional to the force causing it, and inversely proportional to the mass.’</p><p>‘Question number 15 on the 3C Civilization Test passed. The Civilization Test has been passed! We have ascertained that the third planet orbiting the targeted star number 500921473 contains a level 3C civilization.’</p><p>‘Redirect the singularity bomb away from the target!’ The Chief Administrator’s intelligence field flashed urgently, forcefully sending his order through hyperspace to Blue 84210.</p><p>Inside the solar system, the repulsor beam propelling the singularity bomb curved. It bent like a bow hundreds of millions of kilometres long, straining to divert the bomb from its trajectory toward the sun. The force field generator on Blue 84210 was operating at maximum capacity, and its immense heat dispersion plates turned from dull red to white-hot. The force field it beamed out was starting to make the trajectory of the singularity bomb curve away, but it had already crossed Mercury’s orbit and was now too close to the sun. No one knew whether the redirection would succeed. Through live hyperspace projection, the whole Milky Way was gazing at the trajectory of that foggy ball, and watching it suddenly get brighter. This was an alarming sign: it meant the bomb was already encountering the greater density of particles surrounding the sun. The captain’s hand was on the red button for space-time jump, so as to escape the area the instant before the singularity bomb hit. But the bomb grazed the sun like a bullet, with only a few dozen kilometres to spare. The singularity bomb grew bright as the black hole sucked in the matter from the sun’s corona, becoming a flaming blue-white sphere that became visible at the edge of the sun. For an instant, they looked like a double star system, a sight humans would never be able to explain. As the blue-white sphere whizzed by, the sun’s own ocean of fire dimmed by comparison. Like a boat speeding through calm water, the black hole’s gravitational force made a V-shaped wave on the surface of the sun that spread across a whole hemisphere before it disappeared. The singularity bomb ruptured a solar prominence, making this beautiful million-kilometres-long veil that rose from the sun shatter into a beautiful dancing vortex of plasma swirls under the impact of such high velocity ... Soon after the bomb had skimmed past the sun, it dimmed and vanished into the vast night of the universe.</p><p>‘We nearly destroyed a carbon-based civilization,’ the Senator breathed.</p><p>‘Crazy, isn’t it, a level 3C civilization in such an isolated place!’ exclaimed the Commander.</p><p>‘That’s true, neither the Carbon-based Federation nor the Silicon-based Empire included this area in their plans for civilizational mentoring and development, so if this civilization evolved on its own, that makes it unique,’ said the Chief Administrator.</p><p>‘Blue 84210, stay in that solar system and thoroughly examine the level of civilization across the entire surface of Planet No. 3. Your other duties will be taken over by other ships,’ the Commander ordered.</p><p>UNLIKE the digitally reproduced beings stationed beyond Jupiter’s trajectory, the children in the village school had not noticed anything out of the ordinary. They had gathered around their teacher’s body in the flickering candlelight, sobbing. Finally, after a long time had passed, they quieted down.</p><p>‘Let’s go to the village and tell the grown-ups,’ Guo Cuihua said, sniffling. ‘How would that help?’ Liu Baozhu hung his head. ‘They couldn’t stand him when he was alive, I bet they wouldn’t even pay for a coffin.’</p><p>The children decided to bury their teacher themselves. With hoes and shovels, they began to dig a grave on the hill beside the school. A whole universe of dazzling stars looked silently at them.</p><p>‘IT’S A LEVEL 5B civilization they have on that planet, not a level 3C!’ The Senator was amazed by the report Blue 84210 had sent back from 1,000 light years away.</p><p>Images of the skyscrapers in human cities began to appear in the space above the main spaceship.</p><p>‘They have started using nuclear power, and are beginning to explore space using chemical propulsion. They have even successfully landed on their planet’s satellite.’</p><p>‘What are their chief characteristics?’ the Commander asked.</p><p>‘What would you like to know?’ Blue 84210’s duty-officer replied.</p><p>‘For instance, what is the level of hereditary biological memory on this planet?’ ‘They don’t inherit memories biologically. All their memories are acquired.’ ‘How do individual beings communicate among themselves, then?’</p><p>‘By a primitive and unusual means. They have a very thin organ inside their bodies which, when it vibrates in the chiefly nitrogen- and oxygen-based atmosphere of the planet, creates sound waves. They encode the information they want to convey in these sound waves, and the recipient absorbs this from the sound waves via another thin-membrane organ.’</p><p>‘How fast is this means of communication?’</p><p>‘One to ten bits per second.’</p><p>‘What?’ Everyone on the spaceship began to laugh.</p><p>‘It really is one to ten bits per second. We didn’t believe it either, but we’ve checked time and again.’</p><p>‘Captain, are you some kind of imbecile?’ the Commander fumed. ‘Are you trying to tell us that a species of being without inherited memory, that communicates via sound waves, and only manages to convey between an unimaginable one and ten bits of information per second, created a level 5B civilization that evolved of its own accord without external help from higher civilizations?’</p><p>‘Sir, those are the facts.’</p><p>‘But under these circumstances, these beings would simply be unable to accumulate and convey information between generations, which is crucial for an evolving civilization.’</p><p>‘There are a certain number of individuals dispersed throughout the population who serve as the medium conveying knowledge between two generations of these beings.’</p><p>‘It sounds like a myth.’</p><p>‘It’s true that such a concept existed in the remote antiquity of Milky Way civilizations,’ the Senator said, ‘but even then it was very rare. No one knows about it except those of us who specialize in the history of how galactic civilizations evolved.’</p><p>‘You mean the individuals that communicate knowledge between two generations of living beings?’</p><p>‘They are called teachers.’</p><p>‘Teach-ers?’</p><p>‘Yes, it’s an archaic word that has long since disappeared, very rare, you can’teven find it in most databases of ancient words.’</p><p> Now the images sent back from the solar system zoomed out, showing a blue planet revolving slowly through space.</p><p>‘During the Milky Way’s federal period, independently evolved civilizations have been very rare, and as for a 5B civilization—this is the only one. We should allow this civilization to continue evolving undisturbed. Further observation and study will contribute to our understanding of ancient civilizations, and it may also be significant for today’s Milky Way civilization,’ said the Chief Administrator.</p><p>‘So let’s have Blue 84210 leave that solar system immediately, and designate a 100-light year radius around this star to be a no-fly zone,’ the Commander said.INSOMNIACS in the northern hemisphere would have seen the sky shudder with circular ripples that appeared to start from a point in the sky and expand outwards, as though the sky were a clear pool of water touched by a fingertip.The space-time warp caused by Blue 84210’s space-time jump had greatly weakened by the time it reached the earth, merely making all the clocks there three seconds faster. But human beings living in three-dimensional space would have had no way of noticing this.</p><p>This desolate mountainous region was one of the poorest in the entire country. But being poor
            wasn’t the worst of it. The worst was how numb to their condition people had become. He
            remembered many years ago, when it came time to fix household farm quotas, the village began
            dividing up the fields and then went on to divide up other things. As for the village’s only tractor,
            nobody could decide how to divide the cost of fuel or arrange a time schedule for its use. Finally
            they settled on the only solution everyone could live with and divided up the tractor itself.
            Literally divided it up: you’ll take the wheels, they’ll take the axle.</p>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>